urli.st 2012-12-15

# Privacy Policy — Urlist

  * About
  * Bookmarklet
  * Privacy
  * Terms

Latest Update: January 5, 2012

Urlist S.r.l. (the "Website") is committed to safeguarding the privacy of its website visitors . Urlist S.r.l. believes that it is fundamental that its users know and select how his/her personal data hould be treated by the Website.

This policy sets out how the user’s personal information is processed and managed Please read carefully this notice of information; it concerns both registered and unregistered users.

## 1\. Collection and Storage of Personal Data

### 1.1 Personal Data

The users' data will be collected and processed by Urlist S.r.l. with registered office in via Cicco Simonetta 16/A, 20123, Milan, Italy (the "Owner"), as follows.

In the Website's "sign in" box , the user is required to fill in a form and provide information and personal data, i.e. username, first name, last name, email address. All the requested data are essential and their submission is compulsory in order to complete the registration procedure and access the Website's services. 

Registration to the Website may also be performed through the User's Google or Twitter or Facebook account; Accordingly, Google or Twitter or Facebook terms and conditions concerning the exchange of data for direct access to third parties' websites shall apply, and the Owner will collect the user's information and personal data necessary for the registration precedure.

In addition, whenever the user willingly sends an e-mail to the e-mail addresses indicated on the Website, the Owner shall collect the sender's e-mail address, so that the sender's requests may be replied to, along with the personal data provided by the sender within the message.

### 1.2 Other Information

During its normal function the technological platform of the Website collects further information belonging to both registered and unregistered users whose transfer is performed according to the Internet communication protocols. Such information is not collected to be associated with a user profile, but it may be tracked if necessary. By way of example such information includes: IP addresses, domain names, URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) addresses of the requested resources, the request time, the system used to send the request to servers, the dimension of the file received, the numerical code indicating the status of the answer given by the server (success, error, etc.) and others parameters relating to the operating system and the computing environment of the user.

### 1.3 Cookies

No personal data is acquired through the Website in this respect.

No cookies are used for the transmission of personal information. Neither persistent cookies or tracing systems are used. The use of session cookies is limited to the transfer of session identifiers (random numbers created by the server) necessary to guarantee the secure and efficient usage of the Website. The session cookies used by the Website do not entail the use of other computing techniques potentially prejudicial for the privacy of navigation and do not allow the collection of the user's personal data.

### 1.4 Sensitive Data

Please do not submit data that can be defined as sensitive data, such as personal data covering health, sexual behavior, racial or ethnic origin and religious belief or political opinions. In case the user should give such data, they will not be processed by the Owner, unless the user's prior written consent thereto is obtained.

## 2 Use and Purposes of the Processing of Collected Personal Data

**2.1** The users' personal data will be collected and stored by the Owner, directly by its managers or the persons in charge of the processing thereof on electronic and printed media protected by security measures so that they are processed uniquely by the Owner, the managers or the persons in charge of their processing. 

**2.2** The data will be processed manually and/or electronically in accordance with the user's expressed consent upon the collection of such data or subsequently for the following purposes: **(a)** access and fruition of the Website and its services and/or initiatives offered by the Website; 

**(b)** activities that are accessory and/or instrumental to those indicated at previous letter (a); 

**(c)** administrative obligations and/or obligations imposed by laws and regulations, including those in force in the European Union; 

**(d)** sending newsletters; 

**(e)** marketing activities related to the services used, or the lists of the Website viewed/submitted by the user, including promotions of new products or services or commercial promotions and offers of the Owner or third parties, by means of promotional emails (direct mail).

**2.3** The registered user's personal data (described in the section "Personal Data") and the information acquired through the Website platform (described in the section "Other information") can be used, directly by the Owner or by third parties, to obtain statistic and anonymous information about the users and their use of the Website, also to check the functioning therof and, if necessary, to ascertain liability in the event of computer crimes damaging the Website. 

## 3\. Consent to the Processing of Personal Data

For the purposes indicated above, whereby the user is requested to grant his/her consent (in compliance with Italian D.Lgs. 196/2003), the user's personal data will be transmitted to third parties, whereas they shall not be spread, save for the provision under 2.3 above, according to which the data can be transmitted to third parties to obtain statistic and anonymous information. 

Without limiting the foregoing, the user's personal data will be transmitted to third parties who entitled by the Owner as managers or persons in charge of the processing of such data, in that case these third parties will act on behalf of the Owner and in accordance with agreements that conform to the provisions of law.

We inform that for the purposes under 2.2 items a), b), c) above, the user's consent is compulsory and the registration and the access to the Website and its services cannot be rendered to the user without his/her consent (in compliance with Italian D.Lgs. 196/2003) to the processing of the user's personal. As regards the purposes under 2.2 items d) and e) above, the user's consentis not compulsory. If the consent is denied, the user will not receive newsletters or commercial e-mails.

## 4\. Linking to Other Websites

We inform that whilst visiting the Website the user could be redirected through links to other websites which may collect data out of the Owner's control. The processing ofpersonal data collected by such websites is governed by the privacy rules therof.

## 5\. The User's Rights

**5.1** In compliance witharticle 7 of Italian D.Lgs. 196/2003 the user may exercise the rights listed therein, whereof the principal ones are isted below: 

**(a)** demand to validate of the existence of his/her personal data; 

**(b)** demand to delete, unpersonalize, freeze personal data whenever they are processed unlawfully; 

**(c)** demand to update, correct and, if necessary, to supplement personal data; 

**(d)** object, to the whole or partial processing of personal data. 

The rights above enumerated can be practised by contacting the Owner's given address or the following e-mail address : privacy [at] urli [dot] st. 

**5.2** In addition, the user can modify, update, or correct his/her data , and even delete them by following the procedures described in the Website. If the user has questions about the use of his personal data, he can contact the address or e-mail above. A complete list of the managers of personal data is available by contactsthe address indicated above. 

**5.3** In case of request of deletion, the user's personal data will not be utilized and will be kept stored so that the user might re-access them in the future. Such data will finally be deleted after three months from the request of deletion.

## 6\. Notices of Policy Changes

This notice of information may be modified and its terms and conditions may change. The Owner will periodically publish the latest updated version hereof on the Website.
